CV

Sokolik Grigorii

September 2, 2023

About

I am a backend developer with more than 10 years of experience. Most of the time I more or less dealt with PHP. Last 5 years I actively use Go. I have accepted pull requests in PHP source and big opensource projects both on PHP and Go (like codeception, etcd etc.) and some contributions to Linux coreutils. Also I have a bit of experience of managing up to 5 members remote development team.

Experience

October 2022 - Present: Smartly.io (Data Engineer)

Goals & achievements

- Adopted kafka-connect to the company, with allowed to reduce backend services integration process form more than
 month to 2 days.
- Adopted Strimzi kafka operator to provide zero-cost Kafka-as-a-Service for development environmnt.
- Developed and implemented TypeScript code generator to enforce analytical events structure and integrate with Segment tracking plan.

The chnology & infrostructure stack

Python, TypeScript, SQL, DBT, Kubernetis, Kafka, Kafka-connect, Debezium, Ansible, Aiflow

Development & management tools & services

Git, Github, Github Actions, Atlassian products, NeoVim, JFrog products

September 2019 - September 2022: Smartly.io (Software Engineer)

Thechnology & infrostructure stack

PHP, TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Angular, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Redis, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, MongoDB Development & management tools & services

Git, Github, Jenkins, Github Actions, Atlassian products, JetBrains products, JFrog products

July 2019 - September 2019: Kurshi Games (Backand advisor)

The chology & infrostructure stack

GCP, GCE, GKE, Golang, PHP, Docker, Kubernetes, Redis, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Kafka, Vertica, Appache Airflow Development & management tools & services

Git, Gitlab, Google Cloud Builds, Vim

February 2019 - May 2019: Acronis (Senior developer)

The chnology & infrostructure stack

Linux, OpenVZ, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Percona, RabbitMQ, Golang, Python, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Jenkins, PyPi, Git, Vim, Atlassian products, JetBrains products

October 2017 - January 2019: AVITO (Senior developer)

Goals & achievements

- create fast, scalable and flexible analytic tool for professional users (very similar to google analytics)
- increase stability of several applications
- begin to lead team (solve internal problems, watch out for motivation etc...)

The chnology & infrostructure stack

Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, PostgreSQL, Vertica, ClickHouse, MongoDB, Reddis, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Golang, PHP7, PHP-FPM, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Composer, Git, Vim, Atlassian products, JetBrains products

May 2016 - October 2017: Ronte Limited (Team lead)

Goals & achievements

- create project's core architecture (secure chat + p2p calls)
- manage tasks for my programmers
- review code
- manage continuous integration tools
- deploy

Thechnology & infrostructure stack

Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, MongoDB, ZeroMQ, Reddis, Golang, PHP7, PHP-FPM, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Jira, Jenkins, Composer, Git, Bitbucket, Vim

August 2015 - May 2016: Delivery club LLC (Senior developer, mobile API expert)

Goals & achievements

- refactor ugly cms-like code, implement basic MVC patterns
- develop and integrate new oauth-like security policies
- provide unit-test coverage
- provide guaranties of backward compatibility to previous API versions
- solve daily problems

Thechnology & infrostructure stack

IBM WebSphere, CentOS Linux, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Elastic search, Memcached, PHP, PHP-FPM, Nginx Development & management tools & services

Jira, Confluence, Vagrant, Puppet, TeamCity, Capistrano, Composer, NewRelic, Kibana, Git, Github, Vim, PhpStorm

Aplil 2015 - August 2015: Badoo LTD (Senior developer, billing)

Goals & achievements

- Migrate some payment system integration's from oldstyle PHP4 code to modern ones
- Solving daily problems

Thechnology & infrostructure stack

 \dots (NDA-protected Virtualization level), Suse Linux, Mysql, Memcached, CPQ (Cross-Platform-Queue): NDA-protected prortietary Mysql-based queue, C/C++ daemons, RRD, PHP, PHP-FPM, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Jira, Confluence, google infrostructure, TeamCity, Splunk, self-written tools, Git, Subversion (they really use both), Vim, PhpStorm

August 2013 - March 2015: LLC GENES1S INTELLECTUAL SOLUTIONS (Lead developer)

Goals & achievements

- Development management of closed indoor ERP system for binary options and bets companies.
- Management group up to 5 developers
- Dealing with designers
- Participation in negotiations with clients to introduce products and discuss technical issues

The chnology & infrostructure stack

Linux, Mysql, Redis, Memcached, Python (with NumPy/SciPy & Pandas), PHP, PHP-FPM, Apache/Nginx (I've made the migration), Javascript, ExtJs, JQuery (I've made the migration from ExtJs)

Development & management tools & services

Development & management tools & services

RedMine, Subversion/Git (I've made the migration), Vim, PhpStorm

May 2013 – June 2013: Bradbury Lab LTD (Developer)

Goals & achievements

Development of server-side video stream management application

Thechnology & infrostructure stack

Linux, MongoDB, Memcached, Python, Akashi (Django-based frameworke), UWSGI, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Issue tracker (I don't remember was is Jira or Redmine, but deffinitely one of them), VCS (I'm really don't remember what it was), Salt, Vim, PyCharm

August 2012 – May 2013: Probusiness bank JSC (Web developer)

Goals & achievements

Developing backend web applications:

- http://yourcredithistory.ru
- http://smartmarket.net

Thechnology & infrostructure stack

Debian Linux, PostgreSQL, Memcached, Python, Django, Gevent, Flask, UWSGI, Nginx

Development & management tools & services

Jira, Confluence, Git, PyCharm, Vim, NumPySciPy & Pandas (for analytical models experiments, was not used in production)

March 2012 - July 2012: 101XP (Social game porting engineer)

Role

I used to localize apps, that has been bought from foreign developers and integrate it with social networks.

Goals & achievements

- Zombie Lane porting social game from Facebook (http://www.facebook.com) to Hyves (http://www.hyves.nl)
- Wasteland Empires portingsocial game from Facebook (http://www.facebook.com) to Vkontakte (http://www.vk.com) and Odnoklassinki (http://www.odnoklassniki.ru)

The chnology & infrostructure stack

Debian Linux, Mysql, Memcached, Java, Tomcat, CoachDB, Redis, Python, Tornado, ActionScript

Development & management tools & services

Redmine, google infrostucture, Subversion, Eclipse

February 2011 – February 2012: Game-Insight LLC (Junior programmer, programmer, fullstack developer)

Projects

- Funzay high load social network, container for flash games
 - $\circ\,$ developing some services
 - HTML markup
- Game-insight official company's site
 - o core developing
 - o developing services

The chnology & infrostructure stack

Gentoo Linux, PostgreSQL, Memcached, PHP, PHP-FPM, Nginx, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Android

Development & management tools & services

Jira, Subvrsion, Git (for Android repositories only), Eclipse, PhpStorm

March 2009 - November 2010: Euroinvest LLC (Programmer of IT-department)

Goals & achievements

- $\bullet\,$ developing extensions for MetaStock
- creating models for trading strategies

The chnology & infrostructure stack

Windows Server 2008, Microsoft SQL Server, C/C++, STL, Boost

Development & management tools & services

Visual Studio

Education

2005-2010 - MSU, department of mechanics and mathematics

Core skills

- Knowledge of OOP programming paradigms like SOLID
- Knowledge of main design patterns like Singletone, Abstract Factory, Dependency Injection and so on
- Practicing extreme programming development methodology, for instance TDD or BDD patterns
- Knowledge of main software development workflows like Agile, Kanban

Management Basics

• Jira • Redmine

Programming abilities

- Python 2.x / 3.x
 - o asyncio
 - o Django
 - \circ Tornado
 - \circ Twisted
 - $\circ \ \operatorname{Flask}$
 - o Gevent
 - o SciPy/NumPy/scikit-learn
 - \circ Pandas
 - \circ unittest/unittest2
- GO Lang
- ShellScript/Bash
- Memcached
- Redis

- PHP 4/5.x/7.x
 - \circ Silex
 - o Symfony 2/3/4/5
 - o Yii
 - o CakePHP
 - Composer
 - o XDebug
 - o PHPUnit
- Queues
 - ZeroMQ
 - RabbitMQ

- SQL DBMS
 - \circ MySQL
 - \circ PostgreSQL
 - \circ SQLite
 - o H2
- NOSQL
 - o MongoDB
 - o Cassandra
 - o CoachDB
 - o Reddis
 - o Elastic
 - o Vertica
 - o ClickHouse

Other abilities

- ability to use git, mercurial or subversion version control systems
- strong experience of usage Docker, Docker Compose, k8s and Helm
- \bullet experience of usage $\bf TeamCity,\, Jenkins,\, Travis$ and $\bf Github\,\, Actions\,\, CI$
- \bullet ability to impose in **LaTeX**
- fluent english
- several skills in Java (Maven, Spring 4, GWT/Ext GWT, JUnit)
- several skills in **Android** development
- several skills in Javascript (JQuery, Lodash, React, Redux, Backbone, Bootstrap, ExtJs)
- several skills in C/C++ (CMake, gtest, boost/test, boost/asio) development and linux administration

Contact information

Email
Phone
Skype
GitHub
Dockerhub
City

g.sokol99@g-sokol.info +358~40~626~0274g_a_sokolik GSokol gsokol Helsinki